# RYAN WADE COMPTON

www.linkedin.com/in/ryancompton1

(580) 583-2301 | 236 S. Holly Street Denver, CO 80246 | rwc.llc.logistics@gmail.com

## MANAGERIAL & STRATEGIC LEADERSHIP

### Application Efficiency | Workflow Adaptations | Coordination & Logistics

Highly accomplished operational professional with experience providing leadership and guidance in terms of operational coordination to drive efficiencies necessary to achieve organizational goals and objectives. Recognized for the ability to create safe work environments focused on individual and group performance and productivity. Proven to build strong relationships, with both internal and external customers, through the delivery of exceptional customer service skills.

#### **Areas of Expertise**

- Coordination & Logistics
- Inventory Management
- ❖ AUTOCAD

- Continuous Improvement
- ❖ Acute Analytics & Detail Oriented
- Budget Management

- Strategic Execution
- Mechanical Aptitude
- Safety Hazard Mapping

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**SENIOR TEAM LEAD** 2016 - 2019

#### Green Chef, Aurora, CO

- Ability to lead by example in food safety, GMP cooperation, food preparation, and outbound packaging standards.
- Ability to train, guide, teach, demonstrate, assist, and support team members to follow all job role and responsibilities safely
  within day-to-day production schedules.
- Setup and breakdown, maintain, troubleshoot, and train new operators on industrial machinery Liquid portioners, band sealers, and automated production workstation systems for teams.
- Quickly and thoroughly convey to management regarding any error, altercation, or production problem as to alleviate in the timeliest manner.
- · Always 'Team First' mentality in order to keep necessary pace on ultra-high-speed work environment.

PROCESS TECHNICIAN 2013 - 2015

#### Garlock Pipeline Technologies, Denver, CO

- Conducted capacity planning based on inventory demand, department cell capacity and GPT data schemes.
- x2 Safety Summit Leader and Tour Guide.
- Maintained constant communication with the Engineering team to receive, revise and review all technical specification drawings for in-bound sales/project orders and requests for quotations.
- Successfully administered all work order distribution operations from the front office to the manufacturing facilities.
- Coordinated and managed 3<sup>rd</sup> party laboratory testing procedures on metals and material testing including: Positive Material Identification, Inter Granular Corrosion, and Mechanical testing.
- Served as the Safety Committee Team Leader for hazard mapping while ensuring the organization met ISO 9001 requirements.
- · Implemented capacity planning methods and conducted technical engineering drawing interpretations.
- Increased efficiency through the practice of continuous monitoring materials inventory and order management control.

#### ACCOUNT MANAGER 2011 - 2013

#### Standard Hardware Inc., Oklahoma City, OK

- Maintained strong business relationships with key clients to maximize positive outcomes and sales.
- Responsible for a variety of tasks including the delivery of quotes, purchasing, inventory control and the coordination of binstocking efforts.
- Coordinated weekly bin stock item scans for assorted fasteners to be replenished.
- Managed a number of key responsibilities including the delivery of accurate quotes and purchasing items related to non-standard purchase orders from clients including kitting, custom packaging, importing and custom machined parts.
- Successfully managed the inventory of safety stock with all clients involved in the bin stock program.
- Implemented strategies to effectively manage shipping, receiving and quality control.
- Managed logistics related to present and future purchase orders shipped from the branch.

#### INDEPENDENT LANDMAN 2011

#### Energy Land Consultants, Inc., Edmond, OK

Created accurate mineral ownership reports and abstracts, reviewing courthouse and title records.

# RYAN COMPTON Resume, Page 2 Professional Experience Continued

- Researched complex legal documents related to the assigned section of prospective land to be drilled for minerals.
- Documented and organized names, dates and key verbiage related to ownership percentages for future client presentations.
- Created mineral ownership reports outlining all prospective mineral owners and their percentages on the pay-out of wells.
- Travelled to county court houses to confirm updates and legal adjustments related to potential sections of land in question for prospective drilling.

#### RENEWABLE ENERGY INTERSHIP

2009 - 2010

#### Argonne National Laboratories - U.S. Department of Energy, Chicago, IL

- · Performed wind turbine technology investigations to uncover efficient resources to construct small-scale wind turbines.
- Utilized innovative methods to design a system to generate power stored in a battery and used to operate various devices.
- Completed biodiesel conversation from biomass investigations targeting efficient sources of biomass and determining a successful conversion process.
- Successfully operated a diesel-powered generator using biodiesel converted from biomass.
- Conducted Hewlett Packard 5890 Series II Gas Chromatograph and 5971A Mass Section Detector repair.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bachelor of Science, Multidisciplinary Studies** – University of Oklahoma, Norman, OK (2010) Emphasis: Technical Sciences

Related Coursework: Systems & Operations Management, Manufacturing Processes, Material Strength

#### PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Member - American Association of Petroleum Landmen